Is that sufficient? But you do have certain predispositions that you're giving in the same way in which people from political correctness are trying to say, this is what it means to be a woman, these are the kind of things that it is expected from a woman to do to defend herself.
这样就足够了吗？但是你确实有某些倾向，就像政治正确的人们试图说，这就是作为一个女人的意义，这些是期望女人为了自卫而做的事情。
And it seems to me that you are making a similar claim about, this is what conservative people do, and this is how they always relate to hierarchy.
而且在我看来，你似乎在提出一个类似的主张，即保守派人士的做法是这样的，他们总是与等级制度相关。
Well, I would say that I perhaps am doing that, but I don't see how that's the same as what the postmodernists are doing.
嗯，我会说我可能正在做那件事，但我不明白那和后现代主义者所做的是一样的。
I mean, as far as I can tell, the postmodernists aren't saying that the groups, the individuals within those groups, are characterized by any stable characteristics whatsoever, except for the fact of their comparative oppression.
我的意思是，就我所知，后现代主义者并没有说这些群体中的个人具有任何稳定的特征，除了他们相对压迫的事实。
So I don't understand the first part of your argument.
所以我不理解你论点的第一部分。
I mean, part of the reason the postmodern types have been going after me is because I've dared to say that men and women differ in temperament.
我的意思是，后现代主义者攻击我部分原因是因为我敢于说男人和女人在性情上有所不同。
Which, by the way, they do.
顺便说一句，他们确实这样做。
Now, you know, that's actually something that might be worth just differentiating quickly, because it's actually technically somewhat challenging, but also very much worth knowing.
现在，你知道，这实际上可能值得快速区分，因为它在技术上有些具有挑战性，但也非常值得知道。
I was debating someone on a panel this morning on a TV show, The Right Stuff, and this was a woman who led the women's equality party, and she cited some psychological literature that purported to claim that men and women were mostly the same.
今天早上我在电视节目《正确的事情》上与一个小组中的某人进行辩论，这是一位领导妇女平等党的女性，她引用了一些心理学文献，声称男性和女性大多相同。
And that's actually true.
那其实是真的。
We are more the same than different.
我们更相似，而不是不同。
If you look at our temperaments, there's more overlap than there is variance by a substantial amount.
如果你看看我们的性情，重叠的部分比差异要多得多。
And so even on the temperamental dimensions where there is most difference between men and women, the difference isn't of massive magnitude at the center of the distribution.
因此，即使在男性和女性之间存在最大差异的情绪维度上，差异在分布的中心也不是非常巨大。
So, for example, women are less aggressive than men, which is, by the way, why they try to commit suicide more often, but are much less lethal in their actions.
例如，女性比男性更少有攻击性，这也是为什么她们更经常尝试自杀，但她们的行动却远不如男性致命。
That's one example, but there are many examples.
那只是一个例子，但还有很多例子。
If you draw a random woman and a random man out of the population, the probability that the man will be more aggressive is 60%.
如果你从人群中随机抽取一名女性和一名男性，那么男性更具攻击性的概率为60%。
If you bet on the man, you'd win 60% of the time.
如果你押这个人赢，你会赢60%的时间。
That's not a walloping difference.
那不是一个很大的差别。
It's not 95% of the time.
它不是95%的时间。
You know, it's a difference that is substantive.
你知道，这是一个实质性的差别。
It's significant. It's measurable.
这很重要。这是可以衡量的。
But it's not large by the standards by which such things are judged.
但按照这类事物的标准来衡量，它并不算大。
But that's not the point.
但这不是重点。
The point is that most of the activity takes place at the extremes.
重点是大部分活动发生在极端情况下。
So out on the tails of the distribution.
在分布的尾部。
So here's an example.
所以这里有一个例子。
About 9 out of 10 people in prison are male.
大约有10个犯人中有9个是男性。
Why? Because to be in prison, you have to be the most aggressive person, let's say, in 100.
为什么？因为要进监狱，你必须是100个人中最具攻击性的人。
Okay.
好的。
Those differences at the midpoint are large enough so that if you go out to the extremes, 1 in 100 people, you have an overwhelming preponderance of men.
中间点处的差异足够大，以至于如果你走到极端，即100个人中的1个人，你会发现男性占压倒性优势。
And so you can have your cake and eat it too.
所以你可以拥有你的蛋糕并且吃掉它。
You can say, well, yeah, broadly speaking, men and women are more the same than different.
你可以说，广义上来讲，男性和女性更相似而非不同。
The overlap is greater than the disjunction.
重叠部分大于分离部分。
But that's not relevant if what's being selected is often at the extremes.
但如果被选择的东西经常处于极端状态，那么这就不相关了。
And it often is.
它经常是这样的。
So, for example, with regards to engineering, there's a fair bit of evidence that people who are more interested in things than in people become engineers.
因此，例如在工程方面，有相当多的证据表明，对事物比对人更感兴趣的人会成为工程师。
Now, that's not really going to be, what is that, shocking? Are you shocked by that? You shouldn't be shocked by that, right? You can tell that not only by what engineers do, but you can tell that by how they think.
现在，这不会真的是什么，那是什么，令人震惊吗？你被这个震惊了吗？你不应该被这个震惊，对吧？你可以通过工程师的行为和思考方式来看出这一点。
And you can tell that just by talking to them, if you know a bunch of engineers.
如果你认识一群工程师，通过和他们交谈，你就能感觉出来。
So, and it turns out that the largest temperamental difference that's known between men and women is actually interest in people versus interest in things.
因此，事实证明男女之间已知的最大性情差异实际上是对人或对事物的兴趣。
And so it has nothing to do with competence, but it has a lot to do with interest.
因此，这与能力无关，但与兴趣有很大关系。
And because you have to be very interested in things to go be an engineer, because that's all you're going to be doing if you're an engineer, then only those people who are extremely interested in things tend to become engineers.
因为你必须对事物非常感兴趣才能成为一名工程师，因为如果你是一名工程师，那么你所做的就是这些事情，所以只有那些对事物非常感兴趣的人才会成为工程师。
And most of them are men.
他们中的大多数是男性。
And that's why even in places like Scandinavia, where a tremendous amount of effort has been put into flattening the sociocultural landscape, successfully, by the way, there's still a preponderance of male engineers.
这就是为什么即使在像斯堪的纳维亚这样的地方，已经投入了大量的努力来成功地平衡社会文化景观，仍然有大量男性工程师的原因。
And there's a preponderance of female nurses.
有大量女性护士。
And no matter how much sociological gerrymandering goes on, those statistics have remained quite intractable over about a 15-year period.
无论进行多少社会学的选区划分，这些统计数据在约15年的时间内仍然非常棘手。
And so there are differences.
因此存在差异。
There are differences.
有差异。
They're not massive.
它们不是巨大的。
And then you might ask, well, are those sociocultural or biological? It's like, well, that's a hard question to answer because it depends on how much variability there is in the sociocultural landscape because the proportion by which something is biological versus sociocultural varies with the sociocultural landscape.
然后你可能会问，那这些是社会文化因素还是生物因素引起的呢？这是一个难以回答的问题，因为它取决于社会文化环境中的变异程度，因为某种事物是生物因素还是社会文化因素所占比例，取决于社会文化环境的变化。
That's a complicated thing to digest because you think of those things as fixed, but they're not.
这是一件复杂的事情需要消化，因为你认为这些事情是固定的，但实际上它们并不是固定的。
But what we have demonstrated quite clearly, and this is mainstream science despite the fact that people don't like it, this test has already been done.
但是我们已经非常清楚地证明了，尽管人们不喜欢它，这是主流科学，这个测试已经完成了。
So we developed a personality model that's pretty stable across cultures, purely derived from statistical processes, an atheoretical model if there ever was one, and quite an unattractive model because of that conceptually.
因此，我们开发了一个人格模型，它在不同文化中非常稳定，纯粹基于统计过程推导而来，如果有的话，这是一个无神论的模型，概念上相当不吸引人。
But that's beside the point.
但那不是重点。
Then we saw cross-culturally whether there were differences in the fundamental temperaments of men and women.
然后我们跨文化地观察男女的基本气质是否存在差异。
And the answer was yes, cross-culturally, quite robust.
答案是肯定的，跨文化的影响力也非常强大。
Women are higher in the experience of anxiety and emotional pain, and they're more compassionate and agreeable.
女性在焦虑和情感痛苦方面的经验更丰富，她们更有同情心和易相处。
Those are the big differences.
那些是很大的不同之处。
And they're differences of a magnitude that I already pointed out.
它们的差异已经是我指出的那个级别。
Then the next question is, well, to what degree is that biological versus sociocultural? And it's complicated because that variable depends on the sociocultural landscape, but we'll put that aside.
那么下一个问题是，这种差异在多大程度上是生物学因素和社会文化因素的影响？这很复杂，因为这个变量取决于社会文化环境，但我们暂且不考虑这个因素。
You can determine that by stacking up countries from those who have done everything they possibly can to flatten out the sociocultural landscape in relationship to gender to those who haven't, that are still very stratified by sex.
你可以通过将国家按照在性别方面尽可能平衡社会文化景观和那些仍然非常性别分层的国家进行堆叠来确定这一点。
And then what you do is you look at the magnitude of the temperament differences in keeping with the variability that those countries have in terms of their sociocultural egalitarianism.
然后你要做的是，根据这些国家在社会文化平等方面的变异性，观察气质差异的大小。
And the sociocultural types, the social constructionists, their prediction is as cultures become more egalitarian, men and women become more different, more the same.
社会文化类型，社会建构主义者预测随着文化变得更加平等，男女之间会变得更加不同，或者更加相似。
Sorry, more the same, because it's environmental.
抱歉，这是因为环保的原因，所以会有更多相同的东西。
That isn't what happens.
那不是发生的事情。
Exactly the opposite happens.
恰恰相反。
As you flatten out the sociocultural landscape, men and women become more different.
当你抹平社会文化的景观时，男性和女性变得更加不同。
The data is in.
数据已经出来了。
The experiment is done.
实验已经完成。
Tens of thousands of people, multiple countries.
数万人，多个国家。
And it's not what anyone expected.
这不是任何人预料到的。
And you might think, well, it's all the right-wing psychologists.
你可能会认为，这都是右翼心理学家的错。
It's like all the right-wing psychologists are in this room, sitting in this chair.
就好像所有右翼的心理学家都在这个房间里，坐在这把椅子上。